# **Kevin Howard Eaton, PhD**

201 North Main Street · Salem, NH 03079 · (603) 858-5991 KevinHowardEaton@gmail.com

I am an experienced technical leader with a diverse background in a variety of technologies specializing in architect or senior-level software engineering or managerial positions that are either **Remote or in Salem, New Hampshire**. I am most interested in fullstack development or new technologies and I am willing to learn and come up to speed. I am passionate about Go, Elixir, React and React Native, Dart/Flutter, full-stack Javascript / Typescript, and DevOps tools such as Docker and Ansible; although I have extensive experience in PHP, Java, and Python as well.

# Professional Experience

#### **Chief Software Architect**

Remote, Wagz, Inc, January 2017 - Present

- Serves as the technical leader of software engineering and systems architecture for a smart pet device startup
- Designed, implemented, and deployed a microservices architecture to AWS written in Go and backed by MySQL in AWS RDS, Elasticsearch/Logstash/Kibana, ActiveMQ, and Redis
- Implemented API gateways in NodeJS with TypeScript with user-facing Single Page Applications written in React and hosted on Netlify with Cloudflare DNS
- Utilized Docker, Ansible, Prometheus, and Grafana to manage the system's health and scalability
- Implemented IoT services utilizing MQTT and AWS IOT (Thing and Thing Shadow)
- Implemented and certified multiple devices with Amazon Dash Replenishment Services and Pre-Registration
- Managed a team of Software Engineers, DevOps engineers, Mobile Engineers, Quality Assurance Engineers, and outsourced teams to meet tight deadlines with a high degree quality
- Developed and maintained engineering standards documentations, operating procedures, best practices, audit guidelines, and integration documentation
- Implemented internal and external tools, including custom analytics, reporting, and Open API Standard 3 (formerly Swagger) documentation
- Oversaw the acquisition and merger of two separate companies and teams: Petzi and Link AKC

#### Owner and Founder (Hands On)

KVSS Technologies / Treelight Software, February 2008 - Current

- Owner and founder, responsible for day to day operations, development, and maintenance of customized software solutions and consultations
- Designed, implemented, and maintained numerous independent projects complete with a Gobased RESTful JSON API, multiple mobile applications, and single-page web application created in React
- Sole designer, implementor, manager, and maintainer of KDojang, ChapTrack, and TLSchedule products
- Utilized technologies including Go, Java (JEE and Jersey), NodeJS, Python, Javascript with Typescript (React, Angular, Backbone, and jQuery), MySQL, MongoDB, Twilio, and cloud hosting
- Created Android and iOS applications in React Native or PWA technologies

#### Remote Consultant / Independent Contractor / Senior Software Engineer

Remote, Various, January 2015 – February 2017

- Independent contractor and consultant for a variety of companies, including Texas Direct Autos, ERT/PHT, Data Recognition Corp, and Cognosante
- Senior-level technical contributor focused on architecting, planning, implementing, and delivering key systems using cutting edge technologies
- Focused on full-stack development utilizing Javascript (NodeJS, React with Redux, Angular 1 and 2), Python, Dart, Go, and Elixir
- Deployed applications on AWS, Digital Ocean, and similar cloud providers utilizing cutting edge tools such as Ansible, Docker, and various DevOps and CI/CD tools
- Developed mobile applications utilizing native development environments, Ionic, and React Native

- Implemented and managed data in MySQL, MariaDB, Postgres, MongoDB, and CouchDB
- Mentored and trained junior and senior engineers in best practices and new technologies

#### **Director of Architecture**

Gemr Inc, April 2014- January 2015

- First hired software engineer
- Responsible for overall engineering and technology management requirements
- Designed, architected, and implemented a NodeJS based RESTful API utilizing Express and MongoDB with AngularJS front end and Python services
- Managed a team of cross-functional engineers, designers, and product managers to develop cutting-edge products and integrations
- Implemented continuous integration systems using automated tests and infrastructure deployments to various cloud providers such as AWS, Rackspace, Linode, and Digital Ocean
- Utilized third-party platforms to enhance core product, including LogEntries, ElasticSearch, Stripe, and Redis
- Implemented a DevOps platform utilizing Docker, Ansible, and Vagrant to ensure easy scalability, maintainability, and consistency across various cloud providers
- Utilized PhoneGap / Cordova to deliver a cross-platform proof-of-concept mobile application utilizing web standards

#### **Senior Software Engineer (Contractor, 6 Months)**

Salon Target Inc, January 2014 - June 2014

- Senior Full Stack Software Engineer responsible for implementing a new technology stack and integrating with legacy systems
- Designed and implemented a NodeJS API utilizing numerous libraries including Express, Mongoose, MailGun, and Mocha Unit Testing
- Implemented a full continuous integration system utilizing Jenkins for CI/CD
- Trained entire engineering team on NodeJS, Python, MongoDB, API design, Agile Processes, and Continuous Integration on both AWS and Rackspace cloud infrastructures
- Mentored Junior Engineers to become fully capable contributing members of the team

#### **Vice President of Engineering (Hands On)**

Trunity Inc, January 2010 - January 2014

- Migrated aging infrastructure and code base to modern development stack utilizing AWS and Rackspace cloud technologies and DevOps tools
- Responsible for development of Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Scala server-side code and HTML5 / Javascript front-end for knowledge management platform
- Managed a team of cross-discipline team members in an Agile methodology
- Created a Jersey-based Java RESTful API utilizing JEE 6
- Migrated infrastructure to Rackspace Open Cloud Virtualized servers using Ubuntu, Vagrant, and Puppet tools
- Responsible for MySQL and MongoDB administration and development
- Created Business Intelligence platform for reporting and business decision making
- Managed full-lifecycle projects including mobile development applications and large infrastructure migration projects
- Leveraged existing frameworks and tools, including Jersey, jQuery and Smarty
- Developed several mobile prototypes and applications using PhoneGap and Ionic

## **Professor of Computer Science, Fulltime Adjunct Faculty**

Purdue University Global / Kaplan University / Hesser College, September 2009 - Current

- Developed curriculum and taught classes online for Kaplan University and on campus at Hesser College
- Subject Matter Expert and Course Developer for Dynamic Web Development course
- Focused on teaching .NET, PHP, Java, Javascript, Cyber Security, Network Security, Cloud Computing, Systems Administration, DevOps, Ethics, Software Engineering, Web Development, Business Computer Applications, and the Humanities
- Setup and maintained a Moodle-based online augmentation to on-campus courses allowing students to work on material outside of class

### Software Developer, Technical Project Manager

Endurance International Group, April 2008 – July 2009

- Technical Project Manager and Developer for many web-based engineering projects focusing on internal tools and customer-facing applications using Perl, PHP, and Javascript on a Linux/Apache/MySQL backend
- Managed teams ranging in size from 2 developers to 10 cross-functional stake-holders
- Focused on a hybrid agile/Scrum project management methodology, averaging 3 completed projects or sprints a month
- Responsible for requirements gathering, design, scheduling, task management, risk advisory, development, launch, and documentation of projects
- Simultaneously assisted with development of Business Intelligence and SQL report development

#### **Software Developer**

Independent Contractor through Network Dynamics LLC, Jan 2008 – April 2008

- Lead developer and engineer
- Focused on using Eclipse, PHP, MySQL, and Ubuntu to develop a large web-based finance and tax software application
- Primary developer responsible for taking tasks, business requirements, bugs, and additional feature requests and implementing the desired functionality
- Aided in design and alteration of MySQL schema

#### **Developer**; Information Management Officer

Central Texas College, Bagram Afghanistan Office, May – Dec 2007

- Primary developer responsible for development of numerous web-based applications
- Utilized Eclipse and Netbeans to develop a Java Enterprise Edition web-based testing and scheduling application on a Tomcat and Glassfish web server
- Developed a web-based content management system using PHP, Javascript, and HTML/CSS
- Developed web-based testing software using C# and .NET technologies

### **Developer**; Systems Administrator

US Army, February 2003 – April 2007

- Sole developer and technical lead for US Military unit based in Vicenza, Italy,
- Deployed to Afghanistan in which development and administration occurred in a high-stress and classified environment
- Focused on PHP development on a Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP development stack
- Primary application developed within Afghanistan was a customized Content Management System for the Public Affairs Office

#### Military Status

- Active Reserve Officer (Major) in the Army with three previous deployments and over 18 years of service
- Several Army and Joint commendations and awards for leadership and technical expertise
- Active Secret Security Clearance

### Published Research

Eaton, K. (2016). Motivational factors and educational attainment of software engineers (Doctoral dissertation). Retrieved from Proquest.

Eaton, K. (2015). Chaplain access and posttraumatic stress disorder symptom development (Master's thesis). Retrieved from Proquest.

### **Community** Founder

KVSS Charities, June 2016

- Founder of a 501(c)(3) designed to mentor, lead, and guide women, veterans, and others in technology
- Focused on providing mentorship and assistance to improve the technology communities

#### **Education**

### Doctor of Business Administration and Applied Computer Science (PhD)

Northcentral University – *Cum Laude* 

#### **Doctor of Biblical Studies**

CTS - Summa Cum Laude

#### **Master of Divinity**

Liberty University - Cum Laude

# Master of Science in Information Technology Management

Touro University International - Summa Cum Laude

### **Master of Arts in Pastoral Counseling**

Liberty University - Cum Laude

### Master of Science in Psychology

Kaplan University - Summa Cum Laude

### **Graduate Certificate in Business Intelligence**

Touro University International – 4.0 GPA

### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Touro University International - Summa Cum Laude

#### **Associate of Science in Technical Management**

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University